JEAN CLAYTON SERAPHIN

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced web developer, with over 7 years of experience, object-oriented, user-centered design, easy to use, user-friendly websites. Key skills include: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React JS, knowledge of web servers and mail servers such as Heroku, AWS. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements. Consistently saved costs while increasing profits.

GitHub link: https://github.com/claytonseraphin
Portfolio: https://claytonseraphin.github.io/

WORK HISTORY

Freelance Software Developer, 02/2020 to 01/2021(1 year contract) Bawon Event

Built a couple of projects for abroad clients, the most recent
was for a company in France, I built their website (Python,
JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SEO), applied security and took care of
the whole web server(Heroku), and mail server(Google Suite
Management) (https://www.bawonevent.com/.

Software Developer, 09/2013 to 12/2019 Les Entreprises Deschamps-Frisch SA (http://www.retel.ht)

- Testing and evaluating new programs
- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages, plugins and functionality for continuous improvement
- Researching, designing, implementing single web pages with React Js.
- Working closely with other developers, UX designers, business, and systems analysts.
- Developing quality assurance procedures.
- Coordinated with hardware and system engineering leads to gather and develop system requirements
- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects
- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns
- Gathered user feedback and made recommendations
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans
- Tech tools used: JavaScript ES6, HTML5, CSS3, GitHub, React JS.

CONTACT

Address: Wyandanch, New York 11798

Phone: (631) 819-2595

Email: seraphinclayton@gmail.com

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- HTML5
- Full Stack (Django React JS– AWS)
- DevOps
- Google Suite management
- Vulnerability and risk assessment
- Troubleshooting technical issues
- Teamwork / Collaboration
- French
- Spanish
- Blockchain Developer Ethereum.
- Figma
- OWASP
- Heroku

System Administrator Intern, 04/2013 to 09/2013 Group Coles

- Provided network support and performed troubleshooting to resolve various WAN/LAN connectivity issues
- Applied knowledge of computing systems and software structure
- Resolved issues and escalated problems with knowledgeable support and quality service
- Monitored networks and network devices to resolve technical problems quickly
- Maintained excellent attendance record, consistently arriving to work on time

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering, 03/2013 Universidad Tecnológica De Santiago - Santiago, Dominican Republic.

- Graduated with 3.1 GPA
- Thesis: Software Architecture with The Agile Approach.

CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA Security+ Ce Certification